A Guide to the University of Virginia Anatomy Laboratory Lantern Slides Collection, circa 1920-1965
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
The University of Virginia Anatomy Laboratory Lantern Slides Collection, circa 1920-1965
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-55
7 boxes with the dimensions of 4.5 inches x 3.5 inches x 10.5 inches
Keystone View Company
University of Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Dr. John Herr found the collection in a University of Virginia School of Medicine Anatomy Laboratory and transferred it to the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library in 2014.
Historical Information for Anatomy Education at the University of Virginia
Since its first session in 1825, the University of Virginia has included the study of human anatomy in its medical curriculum. The University has constructed a number of anatomical theatres and laboratories to support this study. It also has purchased educational tools and media for use in anatomy classrooms. During the early twentieth century, lantern slides produced by the Keystone View Company and other manufacturers were one kind of educational media that was used to support the instruction of human anatomy at the University of Virginia.
Historical Information for the Keystone View Company
The Keystone View Company, established in 1892 by amateur photographer B.L. Singley, was a distributor of stereographic images and lantern slides. At the height of its success, the Keystone View Company dominated the stereographic image market, operated branch offices in multiple cities, and sent photographers to all corners of the globe.
B.L. Singley initially founded the Keystone View Company in Meadville, Pennsylvania as a vehicle for mass producing and distributing prints of his own photographic works. Six years after the company's founding, Keystone began to produce stereographic images and would rapidly become a leader in this form of media.
By 1905, the Keystone View Company had become a world leader in stereoscopic imagery and sold nearly 20,000 views depicting a wide range of subjects. However, company leaders recognized that popular demand for stereoscopic images would decline as motion pictures became more widely available to the public and sought a new market for their product. Ultimately, the Keystone View Company decided to enter the educational products market. Between 1905 and 1963, the company produced hundreds of educational lantern slide and stereograph sets and aggressively marketed them directly to schools including the University of Virginia.
In 1963, the Keystone View Company, plagued by declining sales, was bought by the Mast Development Company. The Mast Development Company later donated the archives of the Keystone View Company, which consists of over 350,000 photographic and print items, to the University of California Riverside, where they reside today.
Scope and Content
This collection is divided into two series. The first series, "Keystone View Company anatomy slides", is a nearly complete set of 3 x 5 inch lantern slides that depict black-and-white photographic images showing various parts of human anatomy. The Keystone View Company most likely produced and sold this slide set sometime between 1920 and 1950. The second series, "Cephalapagus presentation slides", consists of 3 x 5 inch lantern slides that were used in a presentation at an academic conference. The presentation was titled, "Dissection of a Human Craniopagus Parietalis". The presentation was given by Robert B. Moore and Arthur H. Wasser of the University of Virginia School of Medicine in 1959 at the annual meeting of the Virginia Academy of Science.
Arrangement
Materials in the first series "Keystone View Company anatomy slides" are arranged in numerical order according to numbers assigned to the slides by their manufacturer. Materials in the second series "Cephalophagus presentation slides" are arranged according to their original order at the time of the collection's acquisition by the Claude Moore Health Sciences Library.
Contents List
- Series I: Keystone View Company anatomy slides, circa 1920-1950, 323 lantern slides (Box 1-7)
  - 1-1 Surface of head with guiding lines drawn, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:1)
  - 1-2 Scalp removed and the sutures shown and blood vessels of Meninges to one another, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - 1-3 Outer surface of the dura mater exposed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - 1-4 Showing relation of surface markings, sutures and blood-vessels of Meninges to one another, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - 1-5 Cerebral hemisphere in situ (from a child), circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - 1-6 Composite view. Guiding lines as related to sutures, principle fissures and convulutions, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - 1-7 Right cerebral hemisphere removed, showing membranes which sub-divide the cranial cavity, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:7)
  - 1-8 Composite view: shows relations of the deep structures to surface markings, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - 1-9 Greater part (outer surface) left cerebral hemisphere (adult male) exposed in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - 1-10 Brain shown in relation to the surface lines on the scalp, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - 1-11 Outer surface of the right cerebral hemisphere, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - 1-12 Basal aspect of the brain, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:12)
  - 1-13 Base of brain showing origins of the cranial nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:13)
  - 1-14 Sagittal section through entire brain hemisphere (adult male) exposed in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:14)
  - 1-15 Dissection showing corpora geniculata, connections of optic tract, and middle peduncle of cerebellum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - 1-16 Dissection of the corpus callosum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - 1-17 Showing cingulum and distribution of lateral ventricles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:17)
  - 1-18 Showing body of the fornix and the roid plexuses of the lateral ventricles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:18)
  - 1-19 Showing the velum interpositum and chopeduncle of cerebellum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:19)
  - 1-20 Two coronal sections through the brain, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:20)
  - 1-21 Transverse sections left cerebrum; the lower surfaces are displayed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:21)
  - 1-22 Pathological specimen hydro-, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:22)
  - 1-23 Brain from above and behind showing brain-stem and system of ventricular cavities, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:23)
  - 1-24 The cerebellum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:24)
  - 1-25 Island of reil, or insula, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:25)
  - 1-26 Tracts of long association fibres, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:26)
  - 1-27 Lenticular nucleus and corona radiata, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:27)
  - 1-28 Corona radiata with the basal midal bundles and pyramid, in continuity, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:28)
  - 1-29 Corona radiata, internal capsule, cruata, pyramidal bundles and pyramid, in continuity, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:29)
  - 1-30 Basal ganglia and optic thalamus of the right side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:30)
  - 1-31 The cingulum and fornix from the mesial aspect, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:31)
  - 2-1 The roof and floor of the horns of lateral ventricle from below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:32)
  - 2-2 The mesial fillet in the medulla and pons, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:33)
  - 2-3 Cerebellar peduncles and roots of fifth nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:34)
  - 2-4 The corpus dentatum of cerebellum, the cerebral peduncles, and lateral fillet, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:35)
  - 2-5 Front and side of neck, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:36)
  - 2-6 Muscles, etc., of back of neck, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:37)
  - 2-7 Sub-occipital, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:38)
  - 2-8 Portion clavicular head, sterno-mastoid muscle turned aside exposing posterior triangle more completely, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:39)
  - 2-9 Superficial vessels and nerves, side of neck, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:40)
  - 2-10 Spinal canal, dura mater, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:41)
  - 2-11 Arachnoid and cranial sinuses, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:42)
  - 2-12 Brain stem and cranial nerves in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:43)
  - 2-13 Structures piercing the dura mater, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:44)
  - 2-14 Front of neck, anterior triangle exposed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:45)
  - 2-15 Front of neck: inner part right clavicle, and lower part right sterno-mastoid muscle removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:46)
  - 2-16 Front of neck: the subclavian artery, etc., exposed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:47)
  - 2-17 A deep dissection of the root of the neck, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:48)
  - 2-18 Superficial dissection of parotid gland, structure related to it, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:49)
  - 2-19 Parotid gland removed to show its deep relations, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 1:50)
  - 2-20 Submaxillary region, portion horizontal ramus of lower jaw removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - 2-21 Zygomatic arch, masseter muscle, coronoid process lower jaw, lower part temporal muscle, upper half ascending ramus of jaw removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - 2-22 Portion of the lower jaw removed and internal pterygoid muscle cut short, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - 2-23 Sagittal section of head, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - 2-24 Sagittal section of the nose, mouth, and pharynx, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:5)
  - 2-25 Sagittal section adult, turbinated bones removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - 2-26 Posterior wall of pharynx and adjacent structures viewed from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - 2-27 Cavity of the pharynx exposed by the removal of posterior wall, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:8)
  - 2-28 Lateral relations of rights side of the pharynx viewed from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:9)
  - 2-29 Larynx and thyroid gland viewed from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:10)
  - 2-30 Larynx from behind, B, from side after removing ala of the thyroid cartilage, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:11)
  - 2-31 Larynx, posterior. A, interarytenoid fold, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:12)
  - 3-1 Thorax. Landmarks mapped out and clearly defined, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:13)
  - 3-2 Dissection of the anterior thoracic wall, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:14)
  - 3-3 Wall of thorax, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:15)
  - 3-4 The pleural membranes seen from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:16)
  - 3-5 View of the lungs, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:17)
  - 3-6 Pleural cavity and lower border of lung viewed from right side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:18)
  - 3-7 Lower lateral limit of pleural cavity and lung viewed from the left, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:19)
  - 3-8 The heart and pericardium with the sternum and left linug in position, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:20)
  - 3-9 Pericardium, phrenic nerves, and thymus gland, seen from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:21)
  - 3-10 Relation of heart to the intercostal spaces, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:22)
  - 3-11 Interior of heart, right side, showing valves, etc., in position, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:23)
  - 3-12 Interior of right auricle and ventricle in topographical relation to chest wall, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:24)
  - 3-13 Heart and ventricle, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:25)
  - 3-14 Position of the valves in relation to the chest wall, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:26)
  - 3-15 Superior aperture of thorax, structures pass through it, front view, slightly from above, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:27)
  - 3-16 Lungs, pleura, etc., in situ, from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:28)
  - 3-17 Aorta, heart, spleen, liver, etc., from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:29)
  - 3-18 Aorta, heart, spleen, etc. in topographical relation to the spine and ribs, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:30)
  - 3-19 Back. Thoracic organs, in situ, from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:31)
  - 3-19 Back. Thoracic organs, in situ, from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:31)
  - 3-20 Organs of thorax in topographical relation to the spine and ribs, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:32)
  - 3-21 Heart and pericardium. Two specimens viewed from in front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:33)
  - 3-22 Heart and pericardium. Two specimens viewed from behind and slightly from below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:34)
  - 3-23 Heart and pericardium. Two specimens viewed from the left, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:35)
  - 3-24 Heart and pericardium. Two specimens viewed from the right side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:36)
  - 3-25 Heart and pericardium. Viewed from below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:37)
  - 3-26 Interior right auricle and ventricle, seen from the right, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:38)
  - 3-27 Heart, left auricle and ventricle, showing the chordae tendinae, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:39)
  - 3-28 Heart and pericardium. Interior of left auricle seen from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:40)
  - 3-29 Interior right auricle and both venticles from calvaria, showing interior, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:41)
  - 3-30 Heart and pericardium. Back wall of pericardium showing opening for vessels, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:42)
  - 3-31 Heart and pericardium. Auricular and ven-adjacent parts of arytenoid cartilages removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:43)
  - 3-32 Three views of sections through the ventricular portion of the heart, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:44)
  - 4-1 Mediastina. Interior of thorax, after removing thymus gland, pericardium, and its contents, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:45)
  - 4-2 Mediastina. The heart bed, viewed from the left side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:46)
  - 4-3 Mediastina. Mediatinal partition, viewed from the right side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:47)
  - 4-4 Mediastina. Superior mediastinum, viewed from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:48)
  - 4-5 Mediastina. Superior mediastinum and upper portions pleural membranes, viewed from front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:49)
  - 4-6 Aortic arch, posterior mediastinum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 2:50)
  - 4-7 The lungs, viewed from above and in front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:1)
  - 4-8 Mediastinal surface of the left lung hardened in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:2)
  - 4-9 Mediastinal surface of right lung, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:3)
  - 4-10 Upper limb. Surface anatomy of shoulder from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:4)
  - 4-11 Back. Surface anatomy, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:5)
  - 4-12 Upper limb. Surface anatomy of the back, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:6)
  - 4-13 Upper limb. Surface anatomy, front of forearm, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:7)
  - 4-14 Upper limb. Surface anatomy, back of forearm, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:8)
  - 4-15 Back. First layer of muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:9)
  - 4-16 Back. Second layer of muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:10)
  - 4-17 Scapular region. Superficial structures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:11)
  - 4-18 Scapular region. Muscles of, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:12)
  - 4-19 Scapular region. Quadilateral and triangular spaces, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:13)
  - 4-20 Back of arm. Musculo-spiral nerve, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:14)
  - 4-21 Back of forearm, wristjoint. Muscles, back of forearm. Synovial cavities at wrist, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:15)
  - 4-22 Axilla. Outlet of axillary fascia, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:16)
  - 4-23 Walls of axilla, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:17)
  - 4-24 Axilla. Costo-coracoid membrane, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:18)
  - 4-25 Axilla. Contents of, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:19)
  - 4-26 Antecubital fossa. Superficial structures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:20)
  - 4-27 Antecubital fossa. Boundaries of the space, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:21)
  - 4-28 Antecubital fossa. Contents of the space, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:22)
  - 4-29 Front of forearm. Superficial muscles, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:23)
  - 4-30 Front of forearm and palm. Deep palmar arch, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:24)
  - 4-31 Palm of hand. Superficial dissection, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:25)
  - 4-33 Elbow and shoulder joints, from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:26)
  - 4-34 Articulations. Elbow and shoulder joints, from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:27)
  - 5-1 Abdominal wall. Superficial fascia, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:28)
  - 5-2 Abdominal wall. Deep fascia on right side and on left superficial structures of the groin, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:29)
  - 5-3 External oblique muscle and aponeurosis, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:30)
  - 5-4 Superficial abdominal muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:31)
  - 5-5 Abdominal cavity, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:32)
  - 5-6 Arrangement of the small intestine, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:33)
  - 5-7 Abdominal cavity. Bed of small intestine, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:34)
  - 5-8 Abdominal cavity. Peritoneum, posterior abdominal wall, and caecum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:35)
  - 5-9 Viscera in a female subject, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:36)
  - 5-10 Abdominal cavity. Small intestine, portion of colon removed. Caecum opened. Stomach, pyloric opening, appendix, liver, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:37)
  - 5-11 Abdominal cavity. General view of posterior abdominal wall, viscera resting on it, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:38)
  - 5-12 Abdominal cavity. Position of abdominal and thoracic viscera, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:39)
  - 5-13 Abdominal cavity. Caecum and appendix, etc. in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:40)
  - 5-14 Kidneys, duodenum, pancreas, etc., in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:41)
  - 5-15 The abdominal aorta, the bed of kidneys, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:42)
  - 5-16 Bladder, prostate, and seminal vesicles, seen from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:43)
  - 5-17 Bladder. Two specimens, bladder, prostate, etc., viewed from below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:44)
  - 5-18 Two specimens of bladder, prostate and seminal vesicles, from the side, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:45)
  - 5-19 Inguinal region. Superficial dissection, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:46)
  - 5-20 Inguinal region. Saphenous opening and external abdominal ring, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:47)
  - 5-21 Inguinal region. Inguinal canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:48)
  - 5-22 Inguinal region. Posterior wall of inguinal canal, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:49)
  - 5-23 Inguinal region. Inguinal canal and sheath of rectus abdominis, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 3:50)
  - 5-24 Inguinal region. Showing inguinal canal and adjacent regions on both sides of the body, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:1)
  - 5-25 Lumbar region, superficial muscles, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:2)
  - 5-26 Erector spinae and other deep muscles, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - 5-27 Posterior relations of the kidneys, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - 5-28 Lumbar region. Kidneys and adjacent viscera from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - 5-29 Lumbar region. Anterior relations of the right kidney from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:6)
  - 6-1 Viscera. Stomach, liver, and duodenum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - 6-3 Viscera. The stomach viewed from above and somewhat in front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - 6-4 Viscera. The stomach viewed from behind and below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - 6-5 Viscera. Abdominal portion of oesophagus and part of the liver bed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - 6-6 Viscera. Spleen, pancreas, kidney, and under surface of the stomach, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - 6-7 Viscera. Relations of duodenum and pancreas, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - 6-8 Viscera. Duodenum, pancreas, and bile-ducts, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - 6-9 Viscera. The liver viewed from above, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - 6-10 Viscera. The liver viewed from behind and below, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:16)
  - 6-11 Viscera. The liver bed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:17)
  - 6-12 Viscera. Two spleens, viewed from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:18)
  - 6-13 The caecum and appendix, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:19)
  - 6-14 Mucous membrane of intestine, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:20)
  - 6-15 Viscera. Kidneys from front, upper pair from younger subject, lower from an adult, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:21)
  - 6-16 Viscera. Kidneys from behind, upper pair from a young subject, the lower from [remaining text missing], circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:22)
  - 6-17 Inner border of right kidney, viewed from inside, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:23)
  - 6-18 Viscera. Suprarenal capsules, viewed from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:24)
  - 6-19 Viscera. Suprarenal capsules, viewed from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:25)
  - 6-20 Viscera. Pancreas and bile-ducts from bladder, from the perineum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:26)
  - 6-21 Viscera. Pancreatic and bile-ducts the perineum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:27)
  - 6-22 Male perineum. Superficial muscles, etc., circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:28)
  - 6-23 Male perineum. Root of penis, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:29)
  - 6-24 Male perineum. Triangular ligament, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:30)
  - 6-25 Male perineum. Structures covered by triangular ligament, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:31)
  - 6-26 Male perineum. Prostate gland from the perineum, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:32)
  - 6-27 Female perineum. Superficial struclation to the pubic arch, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:33)
  - 6-28 Female perineum. Triangular ligatures, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:34)
  - 6-29 Female perineum. Levantor ani and from young subject, lower from an adult, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:35)
  - 6-30 Female perineum. Bladder, etc. in relation to the pubic arch, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:36)
  - 7-2 Male pelvis, median sagittal section, viscera from right, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:37)
  - 7-3 Sagittal section of male pelvis slightly to left of median plane, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:38)
  - 7-4 Nerves, vessels, and course of ureter and ductus deferens, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:39)
  - 7-5 Lateral wall of male pelvis. Bladder and prostate in situ, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:40)
  - 7-6 Frontal section of pelvis, with urinary [missing text], circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:41)
  - 7-7 Pelvis: Bladder, prostate, and anterior, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:42)
  - 7-8 Rectum: Posterior view. Male pelvis. Wall of pars analis recti removed, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:43)
  - 7-9 Male pelvis. Relation of rectum and peritoneum to the sacrum and coccyx, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:44)
  - 7-10 Male pelvis. Portion of rectum removed to demonstrate anterior relations, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:45)
  - 7-11 Seminal vesicles and prostate gland: posterior view, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:46)
  - 7-12 Minor pelvis (female). General relations of pelvic organs from above, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:47)
  - 7-13 Female pelvis. Rectum viewed from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:48)
  - 7-14 Female pelvis. Anterior relations of the rectum from behind, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:49)
  - 7-15 Female pelvis. Bladder, ureters, and urethra from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 4:50)
  - 7-16 Female pelvis. Broad ligament, uterus and vagina from the front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - 7-17 Female pelvis. Uterine vessels and contents of broad ligament from front, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 5:2)